

David Solans

Data Scientist

- □ dsolanno@gmail.com
- Barcelona, Spain

About me

I am a Data and Research Scientist with a special interest in innovative data-oriented projects.

After many years working inside the industry in R&D projects, I decided to continue my education with a specialization in Data Science and Machine Learning through a Masters of Science and a Ph.D. in Algorithmic Fairness that I'm close to finalize.

During my career, I was author and/or coauthor of 15 research publications and 5 patents published in the U.S. patents office.

Awards

- 2017 Cajamar University Hack -Data Visualization, 2nd prize
- 2015 BBVA Innova Challenge -1st Prize in Apps for companies
- 2013 BBVA Innova Challenge -2nd Prize in Apps for companies

Relevant experience

Ph.D Student Universitat Pompeu Fabra

Barcelona Oct. 2018 - Present

- Research and publication of peer-reviewed scientific work
- Advanced analysis of large data volumes
- Institutional representation in the EU Commission
- Collaboration with industrial and academic partners
- Communication of research outcomes
- Teaching undergraduate courses
- Supervision of Bachelor's degree and Msc. thesis

Research Engineer CA Technologies

Barcelona May 2015 - Oct. 2018

- Lead the technical development and design of the microservices architecture of ALOHA-H2020 project
- Collaboration with industrial and academic partners on advanced innovative projects
- Implementation and testing of advanced ML-based algorithms
- Extraction of data-based insights from large data volumes
- Development of data visualization for a variety of domains
- Knowledge and technology transfer of research outcomes

Research associate

Barcelona Jul. 2014 - Apr. 2015

- Full-stack development of proofs of concept in the domain of Crowdsourcing
- Research results to product development
- Customer-driven requirements acquisition

Junior Researcher

Barcelona Digital technology centre

Barcelona Oct. 2012- June 2014

- Collaboration with industrial and academic partners
- Data analysis of mobility and platform interaction data
- Full-stack development in research-oriented projects

Education

Currently Ph.D. in Algorithmic Fairness

Universitat Pompeu Fabra

2018 Msc. Data Science Foundations

Universitat de Barcelona

2017 Postgraduate in Data Science

Universitat de Barcelona

2013 Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

Universitat de Barcelona